<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[General Anaesthetic Dentistry]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[General Anaesthetic Dentistry]]></description>
        <link>http://general-anaesthetic-dentist.co.uk/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 17:51:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://general-anaesthetic-dentist.co.uk/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 17:51:43 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>General Anaesthetic Dental procedures</p>,<p>We are the only Private Dental Clinic in the UK offering Treatment safely using General Anesthetic ,conscious Sedation as well as local Anaesthetic for the required procedures.</p>,<p>For our General Anaesthetic cases we need to use a theatre facility for your safety.</p>,<p>Dedicated and well trained professionals guide you through the process which will result in a smooth process to regain oral health,Function and Aesthetics.</p>,<p>This can be achieved by using various options depending on budget and suitability.</p>,<p>The restorative aspect can be achieved by dentures ,crown and bridgework and or implants.</p>,<p>To start your journey to a healthier and better smile just fill in our form and we will be in touch shortly.</p>,<p>In order to give you an idea of our prices we will give you a guide for our fees for the use of a theatre facility including our consultant Anaesthetist service :</p>,<p>Theatre fee per hour : £999</p>,<p>Dental Fees : depending on treatment required but comparable to private</p>,<p>dental practice fees.</p>,<p>Please note that we can do any dental work required within an affordable budget.</p>,<p>You will be presented with a personalised treatment plan where all costs will be explained to you .</p>,<p>You will not be pressured into any decisions and we will not start any treatment until you are happy with the plan provided.</p>,<p>We are looking forward to seeing you smiling very soon.</p>,<p>Thank you for your time.</p>,<p>CK Dental Team</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://general-anaesthetic-dentist.co.uk/our-price-promise/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ba86187e-4df7-47dd-968f-f10825d6bb58</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 22:12:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lead Anaesethist]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/1cf6ee5a-26ee-48f0-9bcf-36041a3d7617.jpg" title="Lead Anaesethist" alt="Claudia Paoloni">,<p><strong>General anaesthesia for dental treatment</strong></p>,<p>Here at CK Dental practice in Bristol, we are one of very few dental practices in the UK to offer dental treatment under general anaesthetic.</p>,<p>General anaesthesia can only be administered in a hospital environment, which is why CK Dental, which is located within Nuffield Health Bristol Hospital, The Chesterfield in Clifton, is perfectly placed to offer this service.</p>,<p><strong>Why general anaesthesia?</strong></p>,<p>At our Clifton dental practice, we pride ourselves on our understanding and experience of dental phobic patients – that is, those patients who have a severe phobia of dentists and dental treatment.</p>,<p>We have previously offered these patients the opportunity to undergo dental work under conscious sedation, but although this method works well for the vast majority of people, there are some whose fears are so deep-rooted that they are unable to relax even when sedated, and others who have built up a tolerance to the drugs used.</p>,<p><strong>Who is a suitable candidate?</strong></p>,<p>At CK Dental we are skilled at putting nervous patients at ease. Partly this is because we have created a calm and relaxed environment where we can discuss your procedure in full before you make the decision to go ahead. We often find that patients are able to embark on treatment with confidence when it has been fully explained beforehand.</p>,<p>When this is not the case, and when dental treatment is urgently required, we may recommend that general anaesthesia is used. Dental treatment under general anaesthetic is usually recommended for severely phobic patients, who have not found conscious sedation helpful in allowing them to relax enough for treatment to proceed.</p>,<p><strong>Why does general anaesthesia need to be performed in a hospital?</strong></p>,<p>General anaesthesia does carry some risks, and it is vital that it is carried out in a safe, clinical environment, by an experienced anaesthetist, with expert medical staff on standby.</p>,<p>Because CK Dental is already located in a hospital, we are uniquely positioned to be able to offer this service to our patients without the need for them to enter a new and potentially daunting environment for the procedure.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://general-anaesthetic-dentist.co.uk/general-anaesthesia-for-dental-treatment/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b6096b54-d4cd-4f4a-9665-48e5f5b3838f</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 13:33:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Full mouth rehabilitation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/f9212603-3c1c-4e58-9024-ddcd0f188625.jpg">,<h1>Full mouth rehabilitation</h1>,<p>Full mouth rehabilitation includes various dental skills to achieve a great result.</p>,<p>In our state of the art facilities we can perform any form of full mouth rehabilitation .</p>,<p>If you are scared, worried, unsure we can help.</p>,<p>We can help you to get clarity into your current situation and be there for you with advice , explanations and a full understanding of the options suitable to you personally.</p>,<p>Always professional, friendly and with your best interest in mind.</p>,<p>Please have a look at our website and if you wish get in touch with us.</p>,<p>We are here to help!</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://general-anaesthetic-dentist.co.uk/full-mouth-rehabilitation/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">02cfb089-ca06-43ac-adf3-df5ed4aa5833</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 12:27:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[General Anaesthetic explained]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/612ba2f7-c90f-49e2-ad4f-f129a2b02413.jpg" title="Modern Facilities">,<h1>General Anaesthetic explained</h1>,<p>General anaesthetics</p>,<p><strong>Starting a general anaesthetic (induction)</strong></p>,<p>Induction usually takes place in the anaesthetic room, although you may go direct to the operating theatre. If you have had premedication to help you relax, you may not remember this later.</p>,<p>There are two ways of starting a general anaesthetic.</p>,<p>Either:</p>,<ul><li>anaesthetic drugs may be given through the cannula (this is generally used for adults); or</li><li>you can breathe anaesthetic gases and oxygen through a mask, which you may hold if you prefer.</li></ul>,<p>Induction happens very quickly, and you will become unconscious within a minute or so. People usually describe a swimmy, light-headed feeling.</p>,<p>If it hurts when anaesthetic drugs are given through your cannula, it is important that you tell your anaesthetist.</p>,<p>Once you are unconscious, your anaesthetist will continue to give drugs into your vein or anaesthetic gases to breathe (or both) to keep you anaesthetised.</p>,<p><strong>In the operating theatre: general anaesthetics</strong></p>,<p>When your anaesthetist is satisfied that your condition is stable, the monitors will be temporarily disconnected and you will be taken into the theatre. He or she will stay with you and will be constantly aware of your condition, checking the monitors, adjusting the anaesthetic and giving you any fluids or drugs that you need.</p>,<p>These are some of the drugs you may be given during your anaesthetic:</p>,<ul><li>anaesthetic drugs to keep you anaesthetised</li><li>pain-relieving drugs to keep you pain-free during and after your operation</li><li>muscle relaxants to relax or temporarily paralyse the muscles of your body</li><li>antibiotics to guard against infection</li><li>anti-sickness drugs to stop you feeling sick</li><li>other drugs depending on your condition as it changes.</li></ul>,<p>Your anaesthetist will choose a way of making sure that you can breathe easily. He or she may do this by simply tilting your head back and lifting your chin. You may have a tube placed in your airway. Keeping your airway open is essential for your safety.</p>,<p>For some operations, muscle relaxants, which will stop you breathing, are necessary. Your anaesthetist will use a machine (a ventilator) to ‘breathe’ for you.</p>,<p>At the end of the operation, your anaesthetist will stop giving anaesthetic drugs. If muscle relaxants have been used, a drug that reverses their effect will be given. When your anaesthetist is sure that you are recovering normally, you will be taken to the recovery room.</p>,<p><strong>After a general anaesthetic</strong></p>,<p>Most people regain consciousness in the recovery room. Recovery staff will be with you at all times and will continue to monitor your blood pressure, oxygen levels and pulse rate.</p>,<ul><li>You may receive pain-relieving drugs before you regain consciousness, but if you are in pain, tell the staff so they can give you more.</li><li>Oxygen will be given through a lightweight clear-plastic mask, which covers your mouth and nose. Breathing oxygen keeps up its levels in your blood while the anaesthetic wears off. The staff will remove your mask as soon as these levels are maintained without oxygen.</li><li>If you feel sick, you may be given drugs which will help this.</li><li>Depending on the operation you have had, you may have a urine catheter. This is a thin soft tube put temporarily into the bladder to drain it.</li><li>When you are fully alert, dentures, hearing aids and glasses can be returned to you.</li><li>You may shiver after your operation. If you are cold you will be warmed with a warming blanket.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>http://general-anaesthetic-dentist.co.uk/general-anaesthetic-explained/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">50ff1529-d281-4c56-81cf-e104888b54ff</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 12:25:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Planning your Treatment]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/dc0a397f-1f98-4ea7-81a1-652484950bbc.jpg">,<h1>Planning your Treatment</h1>,<p>Having to face major dental work can be frightening when thinking about the long appointments that can sometimes be involved.</p>,<p>Even though most dental procedures can be carried out under local anaesthetic in the dental chair there are many people that can’t face longer dental sessions or larger operations. This can lead to more problems because people tend to ignore the problems until they are in a lot of pain.</p>,<p>It is a vicious circle for people that are trapped in a place where they would like to have treatments carried out without having to live through them.</p>,<p>Now at CK Dental we teamed up with Nuffield Hospitals to offer a state of the art facility and general anaesthetic solution that allows you to plan your operation by having a clear understanding of the procedure before it starts and to end up with the best possible solution for you.</p>,<p>The treatment steps involve:</p>,<ol><li>Appointment in our Dental Clinic to talk and examine as much as you can tolerate</li><li>Develop a bespoke treatment plan</li><li>Meeting to discuss bespoke treatment plan and procedure.</li><li>Scheduling and Treatment</li><li>Aftercare</li></ol>,<p>CK Dental</p>,<p>Here to help you smile again</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://general-anaesthetic-dentist.co.uk/planning-your-treatment/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">995dca86-ace5-41c8-abcf-cd160c492aa8</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 21:27:16 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Unique Service and Promise]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Unique Service and Promise</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ecf56842-2cb0-4e15-92ef-1efda37ae051.jpg" title="Welcome to our 5 Star Bristol Clinic">,<p>In our brand new purpose build state of the art facilities you will always receive a warm welcoming and reassuring environment designed to provide the best service and atmosphere possible.</p>,<p>we can arrange overnight stay as well as reduced rates at nearby topclass hotels if you should wish not to take advantage of our great private hospital facilities.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/f70c1099-55c3-45e3-8df5-aa7e3f3f2c13.jpg" title="It&apos;s never too late for a new Beginning">,<p>Overview of the benefits:</p>,<p>Peace of mind</p>,<p>5 Star Facilities</p>,<p>proven pathways to ensure safety and wellbeing</p>,<p>Caring and friendly staff</p>,<p>genuine empathy through the whole journey of dental rehabiltation</p>,<p>working with you to achieve best results possible</p>,<p>Dental treatment can be performed under general anaesthetic</p>,<p>reassuring experienced caring professionals</p>,<p>After Care</p>,<p>Our aim is to help you out of the misery that is surrounding you so you can smile with confidence without pain so you can enjoy life.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://general-anaesthetic-dentist.co.uk/service-and-promise/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6586d802-3915-4a35-92b1-b873af40b5c9</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 22:12:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Procedure and what to expect]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Procedure and what to expect</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/7933f4bf-4d31-4667-8ff6-26116c1c69e4.jpg" title="Our 5 Star Daycase facilities">,<p>General anesthesia refers to total body anesthesia. The body is brought to a level of sleep where there is <strong>no sensation, memory or movement</strong>. Anesthesiologists use medications called "general anesthetics" that are given intravenously or are inhaled.</p>,<p>The level of anesthesia is constantly fine-tuned by the anesthesiologist for each patient. General anesthesia is reversed at the end of surgery and the patient is taken to the recovery room.</p>,<p>The procedure for general anesthesia goes as follows:</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://general-anaesthetic-dentist.co.uk/procedure-and-what-to-expect/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8f168c7e-3d6d-490d-94e1-a9ba0f434771</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 17:45:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Team]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Team</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/3baa3c22-8f56-43b5-8bc5-ef85c35821cc.jpg">,<p><strong>Cornelius Krause</strong> – Staatsexamen at Freie Universitaet Berlin Germany, BDS. Cornelius Krause of CK Dental graduated from one of the best dental schools in Germany. In his time in Germany he worked with internationally renowned dentists to enhance his knowledge and practice of minimal-invasive dentistry as well as cosmetic dentistry.</p>,<p>Spending over 12 years working in the UK he acquired extensive knowledge in restorative dentistry ,implants and clear braces.</p>,<p>Mr. Cornelius Krause is a certified Provider for Invisalign, Enlighten and has completed a 1 year course with the ITI</p>,<p> ( International Team for dental Implantologists )</p>,<p>He has a special interest in Oral Implantology and full mouth rehabilitation.</p>,<p>His passion for the latest technology and its implication in to day-to-day dentistry for the benefit of the patient could not entirely be satisfied until the opening of CK Dental where patients can now benefit from the latest technology together with his calm and gentle approach, vast experience and reassurance.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/f8a9764a-e641-457e-adba-1e8fc0e53137.jpg">,<p><strong>Michael Stiller</strong> – Qualified in dentistry from the Berlin Humboldt-University, before specialising in Maxillofacial Surgery, PhD, DDS. Dr Stiller is the Assistant Professor and Medical Director of the Department of Oral Surgery and Radiology at the Clinic of Maxillofacial Surgery, Free University of Berlin.</p>,<p>He has a specialist interest in soft tissue regeneration in implantology and different techniques of both bone and soft tissue augmentation. Dr Stiller is a Specialist for Implantology of the European Dental Association (EDA) as well as a member of leading European and international dental associations.</p>,<p>In addition to his private dental practice in Berlin, Dr Stiller regularly sees complex maxillofacial and implant cases at CK Dental in Bristol.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/54fa1964-3d47-450b-9d9a-f8909cbb4fac.jpg">,<p><strong>Claudia Paoloni</strong> – Qualified as an anaesthetist from Charing Cross &amp; Westminster Medical School, London, BSc MB BS FRCA. Dr Paoloni holds the position of Consultant Anaesthetist at University Hospital Bristol Foundation Trust (UHBT) and has been the Clinical Director for 3 years.</p>,<p>During this time she successfully lead the anaesthetic unit as a pilot site for the Royal College of Anaesthetist Accreditation of Clinical Services in Anaesthesia Programme (ACSA) and she has recently been invited to join the Safe Anaesthesia Liaison Group at the Royal College of Anaesthetists, London.</p>,<p>Dr Paoloni plays an important role at CK Dental, providing a consultant anaesthetist-led sedation service for nervous patients.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://general-anaesthetic-dentist.co.uk/team/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">773ef508-869b-4638-98d8-006c4dc847d5</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 17:45:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Our location]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/298c3ae9-f7f9-4d99-975b-60606b4d0c46.jpg">,<h1>Our location</h1>,<p>Overnight stay possible</p>,<p>CK Dental</p>,<p>Nuffield Health Bristol Hospital – The Chesterfield</p>,<p>3 Clifton Hill</p>,<p>Clifton</p>,<p>Bristol</p>,<p>BS8 1BN</p>,<p>Email: <a href="mailto:info@ckdental.co.uk">info@ckdental.co.uk</a><br>Call: 0117 906 4872</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://general-anaesthetic-dentist.co.uk/our-location/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">355e5245-0b51-4fe5-958d-741c0760357e</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 11:22:56 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJw9j9kKwjAURH-l5N2k4gZiFHGpKyouBV-k7b0moaapaVTw6919PMPMMNNSRxtp9AqbcCKdy4smY2CSggpjxAlpYjQ7GqsLBgxZedgd56vZOmmUwsVgKUWtd0oP5-ouwKCC0zydbOP5frSc3Kdh389EvbI-byBcsavC26umgzpGAATu7AWJd1PgJCeNuk88iUpIx0nNf8J7VmwsoOXkyTqyQmU_y1_45n3SnpkIVCYopS32OdV-AIZvSh8" height="200"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>http://general-anaesthetic-dentist.co.uk/f8d69c42-6ee4-4882-b3fc-b7b211cd3db0/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">f8d69c42-6ee4-4882-b3fc-b7b211cd3db0</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 07:39:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>